（ナレーション）＜西暦２１９９年＞
＜地球は
ガミラスとの戦いに敗れ→
滅びゆこうとしていた＞
＜人類滅亡まで　あと１年＞
＜宇宙戦艦ヤマトは　希望を求め→
１６万８０００光年のかなた
イスカンダルへ向け　旅立った＞
＜ヤマトは　途中
ガミラス冥王星前線基地を撃破＞
＜太陽系を離れ　ついに
外宇宙へと艦を進めていた＞
Balun
（ゲール）
更迭される!?　この私がですか？
Dismissed? Me?
（ゼーリック）総統の作戦に
泥を塗ったのである。
You have brought shame upon Lord Desler's plan!
If you are unable to deal with the Yamato problem,
ヤマト問題を
うまく処理しなければ→
貴様を司令官に推した
我が輩の立場も→
then my own position is jeopardized, as I recommended you for commander.
危うくなる。
Don't worry, sir.
（ゲール）
ご安心ください　閣下。　なぁ～に→
I can deal with one or two Terron ships!
テロンの艦の１隻や２隻！
分かっているだろうが→
I'm sure you already know this,
我がガミラスに
失敗の２文字はない。→
but "failure" is not a word in the Garmillas dictionary.
我がガミラスに
失敗の２文字はない。→
この我が輩にもだ。
は…　はい！
Nor in my own.
Y-Yes, sir!
吉報を待っておるぞ　ゲール。
I shall await good news, Goer.
（ゲール）ザー・ベルク！→
Zar Belk!
はぁ…。
（モンク）司令→
Commander, about that ship we lost contact with several days ago...
数日前より交信を絶った
友軍艦の件ですが。
いい…。
しかし　あの艦には→
Irrelevant.
いい…。
しかし　あの艦には→
But that ship has an Imperial Guard Information Officer on board...
親衛隊の情報将校と…。
It doesn't matter! Only the Yamato does.
そんなことは　どうでもいい！
ヤマトだ！
Find the Yamato, and destroy it!
ヤマトを捜し出し　たたくのだ！
（モンク）ヤマトの予想針路です。→
Here is the Yamato's predicted trajectory.
現在　この
半径７コルム四方の宙域を…。
They should be within this 7-korm area...
（ゲール）私が　陣頭指揮を執る。
艦隊　出撃～！
I will assume command. Launch the fleet!
（航空隊員）よし！
（航空隊員）くっそ…　ははっ！
（玲・回想）
((ふふっ。　気をつけてね　兄さん))
Take care, Brother.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（森雪）
本艦は　間もなく→
Ship now entering warp navigation.
ワープ航法に
移行する。→
All crew, prepare for warp.
総員　ワープに備えよ。
（沢村）もう慣れっこだね。
I've gotten used to it now.
Repeat: Ship now entering warp navigation.
（篠原）気付いたら
もう着いてんだからな。
We warp, and next thing you know, we're there.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ワープ航法に移行する。
総員　ワープに備えよ。
All crew, prepare for warp.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ビィー　ビィー　ビィー（サイレン）
（島）目標座標　入力。→
Destination coordinates entered.
絶対銀径２７４．７６度。
Galactic longitude 274.76, Galactic latitude -12.73.
絶対銀緯マイナス１２．７３度。
距離６３．７パーセクの空間点。
Distance is 63.7 parsecs.
（太田）確認。
座標軸　固定した。
Confirmed. Coordinate axis fixed.
Wave Motion Engine chamber pressure rising.
（徳川）
波動エンジン　室圧上昇中。→
Engine pressure has reached critical point.
機関　圧力　臨界に達した。
５　４→
5... 4... 3... 2... 1.
３　２　１。
（沖田十三）ワープ！
ワープ！
Warp.
Warp!
What is this?
これは…。
（古代進）
いつもと様子が違うな。
This isn't how it usually is.
状況を　確認。
Situation report.
The ship appears to still be in warp.
（太田）現在
本艦は　ワープを継続中のもよう。
（真田）なるほど。　我々は今→
I see.
We're currently inhabiting the 1 nanosecond of the ship's warp.
ワープ中の　１ナノ秒の時間を
認識しているようだ。
This has never occurred before...
（南部）今までは
こんなこと　なかったのに…。
（心の声）≪自動航法室か≫
The automatic navigation room?
Mori, go and check the automatic navigation room.
森君　自動航法室を見てきてくれ。
はい。
Yes, sir.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（真田）
副長より達する。　本艦は…。
Message from the XO.
We are currently still in warp.
（加藤）いいか？
気持ちに迷いがあるから→
Listen, it's your own uncertainty that's causing the blurry vision.
But we are encountering some complications as we assess the cause.
森羅万象　ぶれて見えるんだ。
（篠原）んなわけないっしょ。
Not a chance...
（百合亜）どうしちゃったの？　私。
What's happened to me?
あっ。　ん？
えっ？
うわっ！　くっ…　ああっ！
あっ　んん…。　はっ！
Misaki?
岬さん　岬さん。
うっ　うぅ…。　あっ！　うわぁ～！
大丈夫？
は…　はい。
Are you okay?
Y-Yes!
ん？
あっ。
（島）どこなんだ？　ここは。
Where are we?
各部　点検　急げ。
I want damage inspections now.
レーダー　スキャナー
ともに　反応なし。
Nothing on radar or scanner.
（相原）超空間通信は
使用できそうです。
It seems like we can use hyperspace transmission.
Probably only in here, though.
使えても
おそらく　この中だけだろう。→
Those only resonate within this space. We can't reach the outside.
この空間内で反響して
外部と交信はできない。
艦長　我々は
どうやら　次元のはざまに→
Captain, it appears we've fallen into a dimensional rift.
入り込んでしまったようです。
異次元との結節点→
Where dimensions intersect...
In other words, a dimensional fault?
つまり　次元断層か。
（徳川・通信）こちら機関室。
This is the engine room.
（徳川）
波動エンジンに　原因不明の→
Energy leak of unknown origin occurring within the Wave Motion Engine.
エネルギー流出現象が
起こっとります。
機関停止。
Shut down the engine.
This area's space-time characteristics are inverted.
ここでは
時空の性質が反転している。
Normally, the Wave Motion Engine produces infinite energy out of vacuum.
本来
真空から　無限に　エネルギーを→
取り入れる特性を持つ
波動エンジンが→
逆に　エネルギーを
外部に放出してしまうのだ。
But in this place, it leaks energy to the outside.
Warning. Multiple unidentified objects ahead.
（ＡＵ０９）
警告！　前方ニ　未確認物体　多数！
あっ！　なんだ!?
（一同）あぁ…。
What?
まるで　艦の墓場だな。
It's like a ship graveyard.
They were unable to escape,
（真田）ここから抜け出せず
こうして　永遠に→
and wandered this alternate dimension for eternity.
異次元を
漂流し続けているのだろう。
A universal Sargasso Sea, huh?
宇宙のサルガッソーか…。
I didn't see anything unusual.
特に異常は…。
（真田）分かった。
Understood.
（ＡＵ０９）
１１時ノ方向　ガミラス艦！→
Garmillas ship detected at eleven o'clock! Identified as L-class cruiser.
識別　Ｌクラス巡洋艦。
生きてるぞ！
ガミラス艦　臨戦態勢に入りました。
It's still online...
The Garmillas ship is on alert.
There's only one ship.
敵は　１隻です。　攻撃しますか？
（ＡＵ０９）距離７４５０。
Should we attack?
火力は　圧倒的に　こちらが上です。
We hold the firepower advantage, sir.
泥沼に足を取られた
２頭の獅子が→
If two lions mired in a bog fight one another, both will sink.
互いに相争えば　沈むだけだ。
向こうも　それくらいのことは
分かっているだろう。
I'm certain they understand that.
Captain, enemy ship is hailing us.
艦長　敵艦が
呼びかけてきています。
回線を開け。
Open a channel.
Alpha 2, stand by in catapult.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）アルファ２
カタパルト　スタンバイ。
Cosmo Zero, on launch standby.
コスモゼロ　発艦スタンバイ。
敵艦載機→
Enemy plane has launched.
発艦した。
零式　発進せよ。
Launch the Zero.
（相原・通信）
アルファ２　こちらヤマト。
Alpha 2, this is the Yamato.
アルファ２は　ガミラス機を
第三格納庫まで誘導せよ。
Guide the Garmillas plane to hangar 3.
使者を送ったなんて
罠に決まってるよ。
This whole pretense of sending an envoy has to be a trap.
でも　この空間から
脱出する方法を　知ってるって…。
But they claimed to know how to escape this area.
そんな方法を知ってるんなら
なぜ　ヤツらは脱出しない？
If that's true, why have they not left?
That's something we need to know.
知りたいところだな。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（格納庫員）
第三格納庫　与圧調整　急げ。
Get hangar 3 pressurized at once.
Pressure rising. Oxygen in hangar now approaching normal levels.
（格納庫員）与圧上昇。　格納庫内
酸素分圧　間もなく　正常値。
あれが　ガミラス人。
（相原）一体→
That's a Garmillan!
What are they like?
どんなヤツらなんだろう？
（南部）人間を→
They're trying to destroy humanity.
滅ぼそうとしてる連中だ。→
きっと
化け物みたいなヤツだろうさ。
I'm sure they're some kind of monster.
（島）おい！
Look.
（２人）あっ！
（南部）そんな…。　そんなバカな！
No way...
That's impossible!
（相原）
人間…　あれは　人間じゃないか！
They're human? That's a human!
（島）見たところ
そうとしか見えないな。　それも…。
It certainly looks that way, and...
（太田）女ですよね？
（真田）うむ…。
A woman, isn't it?
肌が青いのね。
Her skin is blue.
（ＡＵ０９　ガミラス語で）
We greet you as a ceasefire ambassador.
（メルダ　ガミラス語で）
Your Garmillan is difficult to understand.
It's fine.
問題はない。
そちらの言語は　翻訳できる。
I can translate your language.
それよりも　一つ確認したい。
More importantly, I'd like to confirm something.
これは　テロンの艦か？
Is this a Terron ship?
テロン？
確か　ヤマトとかいう…。
Terron?
The one called "Yamato" or something similar?
（部下）ディッツ少尉
テロン艦に　乗艦したようです。
Lower Storm Leader Ditz has docked with the Yamato.
（ネルゲ）もし　あれがヤマトなら→
If that's the Yamato,
it's a lucky break for a second-class Garmillas ship like yours, Captain.
二等ガミラス人で運行する
こんな艦に巡ってきた→
チャンスというわけだな　艦長。
ギムレー長官も→
Director-General Gimleh will be pleased.
お喜びになるだろう。
親衛隊め…。
Damned Imperial Guard...
I am Melda Ditz, of the 707th Galactic Theater Air Corps.
私は
銀河方面　第７０７航空団所属→
メルダ・ディッツ。　階級は少尉。
My rank is Lower Storm Leader.
I am the ship's tactical officer, Susumu Kodai.
この艦の戦術長　古代進だ。
我が帝国の領内にも
お前たちのような→
Within my empire's territory, there are others like you, without blue skin.
青き肌を持たぬ者たちがいる。
そうなのか？
Are there?
Inferior races from systems we've absorbed or from colonized planets.
併合した星間国家や
植民星の劣等人種である→
The second-class Garmillans.
二等ガミラス人たちだ。
君は
一体　交渉する気があるのか？
Are you sure you're here to negotiate?
And you ask that I trust someone who brings a gun to meet a negotiator?
交渉の使者に
銃を持って対する者を→
信用しろと？
あっ。
まあ
テロン人は　宣戦布告もなしに→
Well, the Terrons enjoy war so much, they attacked
攻撃を仕掛けてくる
好戦的な種族だからな。
without even a formal declaration.
戦争を始めたのは　そっちでしょ！
You were the ones who started this war!
For generations, my family has held important military posts.
我が家は代々
軍の重責を担ってきた家系だ。
I swear by my family honor that I speak the truth.
その名誉に懸け　うそ偽りはない。
（島）うそだ！　最初に
攻撃してきたのは　貴様たちだ！
You lie! You were the ones who attacked us first!
古代君!?
Kodai?
I'll hear your proposal.
提案を聞こう。
波動砲か。
はい。
The Wave Motion Gun?
Yes.
（真田）なるほど。
理論的には可能です。
I see. It's theoretically possible.
The Wave Motion Gun generates a powerful
（新見）波動砲は　その射線上に
強力な次元波動を発生させます。→
Dimensional Wave Motion along its line of fire.
計算では
この次元断層の→
If we aim at the dimensional fault's phase boundary,
位相境界面を
狙えば→
発生した干渉波で
開口部が→
by our calculations, the waves of interference should clear an exit.
形成されるはずです。
（南部）でも
なんで　ヤツら　波動砲のことを？
But how did they know about the Wave Motion Gun?
（真田）
グリーゼ５８１で使用したとき→
They must have been paying attention when we used it at Gliese 581.
彼らなりに　マークしたんだろう。
（新見）しかし
波動砲を撃てば　残存エネルギーを→
But using the Wave Motion Gun would cost us most of our remaining energy.
ほとんど
使ってしまうことになります。
It would knock the Yamato off-line!
それでは　ヤマトは
航行不能になってしまう！
その心配はない。
そのあとは　我が艦が→
Don't worry about that.
We promise that our ship will tow the Yamato to safety.
責任を持って　ヤマトを曳航する。
We need a weapon to create an exit,
こちらは　開口部を形成するために
その武器が…→
and you need someone to get you out, once the way is open.
そちらは
そのあとの推進力が必要だ。
協力しなければ
脱出はありえない。
If we don't work together, we cannot escape.
信用できないな。
こちらに　波動砲を撃たせ→
I don't think we can trust them.
It's possible they'll let us fire the Wave Motion Gun, and then escape alone.
自分たちだけ
脱出するってことも…。
（南部）戦争の非は　こちらにある…
なんて言いだすヤツらだからな。
These are the people telling us we're responsible for this war, after all.
（徳川）こうしている間にも
エネルギーは　減少し続けとる。→
Even as we speak, we're losing energy.
We must reach a swift conclusion,
結論を早く出さんと
波動砲を撃つことさえ→
or even firing the Wave Motion Gun will become impossible.
できなくなるぞ。
（真田）そのとおりです。→
Indeed. There's no time to hesitate.
迷っている時間はない。
（南部）じゃあ→
Then what do we do? Is there anything we can do?
どうすればいいんです？
何か　打つ手はないんですか？
ある。
（南部・雪）えっ？
There is.
相手を信じることだ。
Believe in them.
≪シューン（ドアの音）
結論が出た。
そちらの提案を受け入れる。
We've reached our decision. We'll agree to your plan.
よかった…　感謝する。
I'm glad. I thank you.
（ラング・通信）こちらは　ＥＸ１７８
艦長　ヴァルス・ラングだ。
This is Vars Lang, Captain of the EX-776.
ヤマト艦長　沖田十三だ。
I am Captain Juzo Okita of the Yamato.
Captain Lang, we thank you for your proposal.
ラング艦長
貴官の提案に　感謝する。
Just like you, we have been stuck here, unable to escape.
（ラング・通信）我々も　君たち同様
この空間に閉じ込められ→
脱出できないでいた。→
こちらも
貴艦の提案受諾に感謝している。→
We thank you, as well, for acceding to our plan.
Lower Storm Leader Ditz will remain there, to serve as a point of contact.
ディッツ少尉には　連絡要員として
そちらに残ってもらう。
You may take it as a gesture of our goodwill.
（ラング）
これは　我々の誠意の証しと→
思ってもらいたい。
ふっ。
体のいい人質ってことか。
So, a convenient hostage, huh?
（ラング・通信）だが
通常空間に出た後は　敵と味方。
But once we return to normal space, we will be enemies once more.
Understood.
承知している。
（ラング・通信）貴艦と→
I look forward to exchanging fire with you.
砲火を交えることを
楽しみにしている。
ピピッ
通信　終了しました。
Transmission over.
If we use the Wave Motion Gun, we won't have energy for our main artillery.
波動砲を使用したら
主砲に回すエネルギーも…。
分かっている。
あっ。
I know.
これは　男と男の約束だ。
This is a promise between men.
So Admiral Ditz's daughter stays with them.
（ネルゲ）艦隊総司令の娘が残るんだ。
The Terrons must trust us now.
テロンも信用しただろう。　ふっ。
（メルダ）美しい石だ。
That is a beautiful stone.
高貴な青には劣るが
赤も美しいものだな。
While not as splendid as a noble blue, red is a lovely color.
（玲）赤は　ふるさとの色。→
Red is the color of my home. And it is my color.
そして　自分の色。
大切なもののようだ。
It seems quite important to you.
（玲）古代さんの銃と同じ。
Just like Kodai's gun.
どういう意味だ？
（玲）大好きだった肉親が→
What do you mean?
Both are mementos our beloved ones left behind.
残したものよ。
Before you killed them all.
みんな　お前たちに殺された。
牽引ビーム　受け入れます。
Incoming tow beam.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウウゥー　ウウゥー（警告音）
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウウゥー　ウウゥー…
非常電源に切り替え。
Switch to emergency power.
始まったようだ。
It's begun.
Prepare to fire the Wave Motion Gun!
波動砲　発射用意。
Releasing safety lock.
セーフティーロック　解除。
強制注入機　作動。
Activating force injector.
Final safety released.
最終セーフティー　解除。
（南部）薬室内
タキオン粒子…　圧力上昇中！
Tachyon particle pressure rising in chamber.
（太田）
ガミラス艦　射線上より離れる。
Garmillas ship is leaving the firing line.
対ショック　対閃光　防御。
Engage anti-shock and anti-flare defenses.
ターゲットスコープ　オープン。
Target scope open!
Electronic cross-gauge, display brightness twenty.
電影クロスゲージ　明度２０。
発射５秒前　４→
Five seconds to fire.
4... 3... 2... 1...
３　２　１。
発射！
撃てぇ～！
Fire.
Fire!
バシューー!!
ドオォーーン!!
Exit has been created.
突破口　形成された。
But now, the Yamato no longer has the power to move on her own.
≪だが　これで
ヤマトは　自力航行できる力を→
使い果たした≫
（航宙士）
次元境界面に　亀裂を確認。→
Confirmed fissure in dimensional boundary. It's an exit.
脱出口です。
This ship will commence towing the Yamato from the area.
本艦は　これより　ヤマトを曳航。
ん？
共に　この空間を脱出する。
んん…。
Garmillas ship has begun to tow us.
ガミラス艦　本艦の曳航を開始。
艦長　まさか　このまま…。
Captain, you don't plan to...
君は部外者だ　親衛隊大尉。
くっ！→
You are an outsider here, Storm Leader.
Hail to our Leader!
総統　万歳！
Tow beam output stabilized and normal.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）トラクタービーム
出力安定。　問題ありません。
The tow beam has been cut!
牽引ビームの接続が
切られました！
あっ！
ガミラス艦より→
The Garmillas ship has sent a hyperspace transmission to the opening.
開口部に向け
超空間通信が打たれました。
暗号化され　内容は不明。
It's encrypted, and we can't read it!
Then they do plan to escape and leave us here!
ヤツら
やっぱり　自分たちだけで…。
信じた結果が　これか。
That's what we get for believing them.
Impossible!
（メルダ）バカな！
（玲）やっぱり…。
I knew it.
やっぱり
そういうことだったのね。
I knew this was your plan!
（ラング）こういうことか。
（オペレーター）艦長　自分は…。
What are you doing?
Captain, I...
（ラング）ゲール少将に
ヤマト発見の報を打ったのも→
You're the one who alerted Commander Goer that we found the Yamato?
君だな？　大尉。
I shall report this treason upon our return.
この反乱行為は
あとで報告させてもらう。
This is no treason.
これは反乱ではない！
反逆者は　艦長…　貴様だ！
You're the traitor here, Captain. They're our enemy!
ヤツらは　敵なんだぞ!?　くっ…。
（玲）あなたは　私たちの敵。
You are our enemy.
敵だと思うなら撃て。　ためらうな。
If you think I'm an enemy, shoot me. Do not hesitate.
ピシュン！（銃声）
牽引ビーム　再接続されました。
Tow beam has been reconnected.
なっ!?
どういうことだ!?
What's going on?
Stay on alert. For now, just focus on getting out.
気を抜くな。
今は　脱出だけに集中しろ。
パリン！
（メルダ）ふっ！
（玲）あっ…　ぐはっ！　んん！→
はあ～！
（メルダ）くっ！
通常空間まで　あと３分。
Three minutes until we reenter normal space.
The exit is becoming unstable.
開口部が　不安定になっている。
（太田）
ガミラス艦との相対距離　変わらず。
Maintaining relative distance to Garmillas ship.
あと１分。
One minute left.
（航宙士）経図に　位相変動を観測。
Detecting phase fluctuation.
（航宙士）
速度１２ガットまで加速する。
Accelerating to 12 gat.
You're a pilot, right?
（メルダ）
お前は　戦闘機乗りなのだろ？
We don't need this thing between us.
私たちの間に
こんなものは必要ない。
（太田）牽引ビーム　解除された。
Tow beam released.
Ship has returned to regular space.
本艦は現在　通常空間を航行中。
やった。
僕たち　脱出できたんだね。
We did it.
We made it out, right?
Yeah, we're saved!
ああ。　助かったんだ。
（太田）よかった～。
Good...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ファン　ファン　ファン…
（警告音）
All crew to battle stations.
（ラング）全艦　戦闘配置！
（部下）全艦　戦闘配置。
（ラング）ディッツ少尉に　帰還命令。
Order Lower Storm Leader Ditz to return.
ヤマトか…。　賞賛すべき敵だ。
The Yamato, huh? A splendid enemy.
（部下）
友軍艦艇　ゲシュタムアウト。
Friendlies are Geschtaming in.
Garmillas fleet warping in, off our port bow.
左舷前方　ガミラス艦隊　ワープアウト！
やはり　罠か！
So it was a trap!
EX-776...
ＥＸ１７８　お前たちは
こちらの射線上にある。→
You are in our line of fire. You're in the way. Move!
砲撃の邪魔だ。　そこをどけ！
ゲール少将！　あの艦には→
Commander Goer, Admiral Ditz's daughter is aboard that ship!
ディッツ提督のご令嬢が
乗っておられるのです。
（ゲール）ん？
（モンク）司令…。
Commander...
（ゲール）ふん！　かまわん　撃て。
あっ…。
I don't care. Fire.
（航宙士）友軍から発砲！
（航宙士）回避　回避だ！
We're under friendly fire! Evade! Evade!
ドカン！
ドォーーン!!
（一同）うわぁ～！
（南部）ＥＸ１７８　撃沈された！
EX-776 has been shot down!
Confirmed destruction of EX-776.
（航宙士）ＥＸ１７８の撃沈を確認。
The Yamato shot down the missing ship we were searching for.
（ゲール）捜索中の行方不明艦は→
ヤマトの攻撃で撃沈された。
そうだな？
That's what happened, right?
Yes.
はい…。
よ～し！　全艦→
All right!
All ships, open fire on the Yamato!
ヤマトに　火力を集中させろ！
ビシュ　ビシュ　ビシュ　ビシュ！
ドカン！
ドカン！　ドカン！
Exterior armor hit, port side!
（太田）左舷　外殻装甲に被弾。
（真田）ダメージコントロール→
Damage control! Hurry!
急げ！
反撃しましょう！
Let's counterattack.
艦首　回頭。
えっ？
Turn the ship around.
逃げるんですか？
そうだ。
We're running?
Yes.
逃がすな～！
追い込んで　たたくのだ！
Don't let them escape! Pursue and destroy them!
敵艦隊　消滅していきます！
The enemy fleet is being annihilated.
A huge dimensional quake!
（航宙士）強大な次元震！　震源で
次元断層が　発生しているもよう。
A dimensional fault is forming at the epicenter.
（ゲール）て…　撤退だ！
今すぐ　この宙域からジャンプしろ。
R-Retreat! Jump out of here now!
（モンク）しかし　撤退命令も出さず
旗艦が　戦線を離脱しては…。
But the flagship cannot retreat before issuing the order to the other ships.
死にたいのか!?　貴様は！
Do you all want to die?
敵艦隊　消滅。
Enemy fleet has been eradicated.
開口部が
元に戻ろうとする反動で→
The exit from the rift tried to collapse into its original position.
一時的に　裂け目が広がり
飲み込まれたんだ。
The reaction temporarily expanded the rift, sucking them in.
はい　分かりました。
Yes, understood.
ピッ（操作音）
あなたの帰るべき場所は→
They said your prior destination no longer exists.
なくなったそうよ。
あぁ…。
Episode 10: Graveyard of the Universe
Everyone lives with secret feelings.
It takes courage to reflect on a horrible past and one's own mistakes.
But look toward to the future.
Now is the time to go forward.
The Yamato advances, on an unimaginably long journey.
Next time: A World I Once Saw.
There are 323 days left before humanity is extinct.
アメリカのカリフォルニア州で行
われた
米中首脳会談が、終了した。
砂漠地帯の保養施設で
２日間にわたって行われた異例の
会談。
果たして、成果はあったのか。